Guide to the Tracy Kronzak papers, 1992-2008
Kronzak, Tracy papers, 1992-2008
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Tracy Kronzak papers, 1992-2008
7599
Tracy Kronzak
2.7 cubic feet
Manuscripts, collected subject files, posters and ephemera, audiocassettes, one videocassette, and photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Materials collected by Tracy Kronzak while a student at Cornell University. Includes material on gay life and AIDS in Russia, materials from the 1996 display of the AIDS Quilt in Washington, D.C., materials from gay/lesbian/bisexual/transgender organizations at Cornell and in San Francisco.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University Class of 1995.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, collected subject files, posters and ephemera, audiocassettes, a videocassette of a debate Kronzak participated in regarding the LGBT Living Learning Unit, photographs, a notebook and other materials of a lesbian/gay/bisexual activist and Cornell University student. Papers include material deriving from and pertaining to Kronzak's two summers in Russia and collected materials from that time on gay life and AIDS in Russia, including interviews with Russian AIDS activists, pictures of gay Russian people and areas, and leaflets on lesbian and gay issues in Russia. Also, ephemera from the 1996 display of the AIDS Quilt in Washington, D.C. Cornell papers include files on Student Assembly, the Lesbian Gay Bisexual Transgendered Coalition, Cornell University Gay and Lesbian Alumni Association (CUGALA), the proposed Lesbian and Gay Living Learning Unit, the takeover of Day Hall, the controversy engendered by Professor Jim Aist's offer to assist in curing homosexuality, and other topics.
Includes LBG Resource Office files; CUGALA files, material on the founding of Dialogue (which Kronzak founded), a multifaith lesbian/bisexual/gay/transgendered spirituality/religious group at Cornell; 1995 followup on Kronzak's complaint about Professor Jim Aist's distribution of homophobic materials; and other records and material on lesbian/gay/bisexual issues.
Original comic strip drawn for Kronzak by Cornell alum Laura Diane Steele, "The Adventures of an Alternative Dyke Ivy League College Student." Also, "It's a Gay Life" comics that hung on Kronzak's room in Clara Dickson Hall, circa 1992-1995, other gay comics, and copies of proofs of "For Better or for Worse" given to Kronzak by a friend at the Cornell Daily Sun.
Organizing files, t-shirts, flag, and other items from the San Francisco Dyke Marches, 2000-2003, for which Kronzak served on the general planning committee. Also, political buttons collected at national and California events on issues of LGBT pride, workers rights, political candidates, and peace, in the 1990s-2008.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kronzak, Tracy.; Aist, James.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University. Student Assembly.; Cornell University. Lesbian and Gay Living Learning Unit.; Cornell University. Lesbian Gay Bisexual Transgendered Coalition.; Cornell University. Gay and Lesbian Alumni Association.; Cornell University. Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual Working Group.
Subjects:
Gays--Russia.; Lesbians--Russia.; Lesbians--Political Activity.; AIDS (Disease)--Study and teaching.; AIDS (Disease)--Prevention.; AIDS (Disease)--Russia.; Gays--Comic books, strips, etc.; Homophobia.; NAMES Project AIDS Memorial Quilt.
Places:
Russia--Social life and customs.; San Francisco (Calif).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
File of interview notes for Cornell Vice President position restricted.
CONTAINER LIST
- Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Coalition, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Coalition, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Cornell Lesbian/Bisexual/Gay Alliance, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Student Assembly, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Working Group on Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Issues, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Working Group on Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Issues, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with President Rhodes re: LGBI Working Group, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- CUGALA (Cornell University Gay and Lesbian Alumni Association): Newsletter, correspondence, 1982-1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- CUGALA Career Network Questionnaire, No date (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Living and Learning Unit: Media coverage, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Living and Learning Unit: Student Assembly Agendas, Minutes, Resolutions, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Living and Learning Center Miscellany, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Gay/Lesbian/Bisexual Resource Office, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Gay/Lesbian/Bisexual Affairs Administrator, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Living and Learning Unit Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Day Hall Takeover, November 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Latino Living and Learning Unit, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- ROTC/Gays in the Military, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Same-Sex Partners Health Benefits, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Residence Life Housing Issues, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Professor Aist/Plant Sciences Actions (News Clippings), 1995 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Professor Aist: Posters, Essays re: curability of homosexuality, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Notes, email concerning Professor Aist, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Formal Actions taken against Professor Aist, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- LGB Issues:LGB Awareness Month, LGB Student Assembly Seat, Equal Opportunity Policy Revisions, Gay Liberation, Student Homophile League, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- AIDS and Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual Issues at Cornell, 1984-1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Political Issue Flyers (Contract with America, Health Care, AIDS Crisis), 1995 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- March on Washington, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Conferences: National Lesbian, Gay and Bisexual Student Networking Conference, Constructing Queer Cultures, Creating Change, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Newsletters (other universities, organizations), 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Columbia University Community News, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Overlooked Opinions, Inc., 1994 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Miscellaneous Flyers, Pamphlets, Articles, Email, Notes, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Film, Theater, Dance Festivals, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Anthropology 400: Interviews, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Anthropology 350: Paper/Interview with Vladimir Sedov, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Anthropology 385: Interview, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Anthropology 385: Paper: "Lesbian and Gay Cornell", 1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Restricted, No date (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Miscellaneous Books and Pamphlets, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- AIDS/HIV in Russia, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Field Notes (on AIDS in Russia), 1994 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Gay Activism in Poland, Hungary, Lithuania, Czechoslovakia, East Germany, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Gay Liberation Movement in Eastern Europe, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Gay Activism/Historical Treatment of Gays in Russia, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Sociology 366: Paper:"A Survey of the Gay Liberation Movement in Eastern Europe with Emphasis on Russia", 1992 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Russian news clippings on AIDS issues, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- AIDS Infoshare: drafts, fund-raising, public relations pieces, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Cornell Correspondence re: AIDS Infoshare, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Anti-Democracy Publication, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Pro-life pamphlet by "Supporting Mothers," anti-gay organization, No date (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Condoms, No date (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Ads and leaflets re: Moscow Lesbian and Gay Events/Groups, ca. 1990 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Moscow Sexual Assault Recovery Center, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- AESOP (An Effective Shield of Protection), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Newspaper clippings and notes from diary, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Diary, interview tapes, photos, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Cornell Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual Coalition T-Shirt and Assorted Buttons, No date (Box 1, Folder 58)
- AIDS Quilt in D.C., 1996 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- Aist Follow Ups, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- CMI/Campus Survey Project, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- CUGALA (Cornell University Gay and Lesbian Alumni), 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- HIV/AIDS Ministry Info from D.C., 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Columbia Takeover, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- GLSTN Info from D.C. (Gay, Lesbian, and Straight Teachers Network), 1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Hammer, Dr. Paul, No date (Box 2, Folder 9)
- LGB Relations, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- LGB Resource Office, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- LGB Retreat, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- LGB Town Meeting, April 11, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- LGB Miscellany, No date (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Outlines Interview - Carlisle Douglas, LGB Resource Center Coordinator, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Dialogue: founding info and 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Dialogue: Fall 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Dialogue, No date (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Dyke March: Publicity and Ephemera, 1993-2002 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Dyke March: Bills and Money, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Dyke March Planning, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Dyke March Planning, 2000-2002 (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
- Five Dyke March T-Shirts, 2000-2003 (Box 3)
- Dykes For Peace, Peace For Dykes pennant (Box 3)
- Small Postcards, Clippings, Comic Strips, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Original Artwork from Laura Diane Steele, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Buttons Collected at Various LBGT Events, 1993-2008 (Box 4, Folder 1-8)
- Buttons in Support of Various Candidates and Issues, California-based, ca. 1992-2008 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
- Buttons from the March on Washington, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Buttons, Gift from Gerard Palmieri: Labor Rights, "Stop the OCA", Stop Censorship, Gay Pride, ca. 1990s (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
- Buttons, California Propositions and Events, ca. 1990s (Box 5, Folder 7)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Periodicals
A&U. 1996: Oct.
Community Ink. 1992: Mar.
Community News. 1993: Nov., Dec.; 1994/1995: Apr., Sept.-Dec./Jan.; 1995: Feb.-May
CUGALA News. 1994: Fall/Winter; 1996: Spring
Firetruck House Flame. 1995: Mar.
Gay Community News. 1993: Apr.
Gay Market Report. 1992: v.4, no.1
HQ. 1992: Dec. 1
HRC Quarterly. 1996: Fall-Winter
In Full View. 1992: v.2, no.1
Michael's Entertainment Weekly. 1993: Oct. 7
Miriam's House Newsletter. 1995: Summer; 1996: Spring
New Hampshire Pride Reporter. 1994: Mar.
Outlines. 1995: Winter; 1996: Summer
OutWrite: A Poetry Journal of Gay, Lesbian, and Bisexual Youth. 1993: June 19
Society of Lesbian and Gay Anthropologists Newsletter. 1993: June
Steam. 1993: Spring
The Other Pages. 1998
Community News. 1993: Nov., Dec.
Comics
Alpha Flight. Vol. 1, #106, Mar. 1992, First and Second Prints
New Bondage Fairies #2, Dec. 1996
Original Bondage Fairies #1, Oct. 1998
Boy Trouble #3, Spring/Summer 1997
Enchanters #1, June 1996
Erotic Adventures of Raheem#1, Aug. (1995?)
Gay Comix #1-25, 1980-Spring 1998
Gay Hearthrobs Vol. 1, #1, 1976
Go-Go Boy #1-3, 1994, Feb. 1995, Oct. 1995
Green Arrow #43, Dec. 2004
Hands Off! #1, Summer 1994
Hothead Paisan #2, 10-17, 21, 1991-1998
Likewise #1, Oct. 2002
Penny Century #1, Dec. 1997
Potential #1-2, Mar. 1998, May 1998
Queer Boys #1-2, Dec. 1997, Jun. 1998
Rawhide Kid #1, Apr. 2003
Small Favors #1, Nov. 2000
Tales of the Closet #1-9, Summer/Fall 1987-Summer 1993
Transforma #1, 1996
Transformation #2, 1994
Watch Out #1, 1986
Wendel #1, 1989
Books
Rieder, Ines. Feminism and Eastern Europe. Dublin: Attic Press, 1991.
Gessen, Masha. The Rights of Lesbians and Gay Men in the Russian Federation. San Francisco: International Gay and Lesbian Human Rights Commission, 1994.